Friends, if the insurance policy of your two wheeler like scooter
or bike
is about to expire or has expired,
then
in this video you will learn how to renew the insurance policy through PhonePe application.  So
watch the video carefully and completely.  So for this
you have to first like the video.
Now you have to go to the description of the video.
I will give you the link there.
As soon as you click on the link, the
PhonePe application will open in front of you.
First of all you have to download PhonePe app on your phone.
If you already have the download, then
you can update it and open it
and log in here with your mobile number.
We are already logged in here.  If
you come down a little,
you will see that there is
an option of bike insurance in the insurance column.  Although there is car insurance
, health insurance and life
insurance too.  So, right now we are talking about
how to get bike or scooter insurance.
Remember friends, it is possible
that the PhonePe application may get updated in the future.
So you do not have to be confused at all as to
why we are seeing the interface in this manner here.  Ok?
So the PhonePe
application keeps getting updated, so don't get confused.  So we will
select the bike here and now
you have to enter the number of your scooter or bike here.
So we have entered.
We will click on Find Plans.  In
this way, what is the model number of your car
?  You will be able to see which company's car
it is.  When
is the registration date?  If your policy has
expired and it has been more than 90 days, then
you will say yes to it.  If it has
not expired yet, it has not ended
then you can mark it as no.  After that
you will click on the view from below.
Now remember, here the
plan will appear at the top in front of you.  Which plan do you want to
take?  So if you click on the plan, there are
basically two plans here.  The first
plan is the On Damage Plan.  Remember this is
for those who already have
third party insurance.  Remember,
this is where many people make mistakes.
Due to which they have to pay more money
in the insurance policy.
Now friends, what happens whenever you
buy a scooter or bike or you do not
buy it or buy it second hand, then
what happens after that, you must have seen
what happens here, first party
insurance is for 1 year and
third party insurance is for 5 years,
so you do not need to take third party insurance every year,
if your vehicle is very old i.e.
more than 5 years old and
you do not have third party insurance, then what will you do,
select the comprehensive plan here, so for now
guys, I have to take the on damage plan which
I have.  I still have another
3 year old one from a third party.  So right now I'll just
select on damage.
But if you do not have it then you can
select it as comprehensive.  Ok
?  Also RDB.  RDB stands for
Insured Declared Value.  That is,
God forbid your vehicle ever gets totaled.  If
your car gets stolen or
catches fire, then
how much money will the insurance policy give
you for that car, that is what RDB value means here.
So we will select above RDB.
And what will we do here?  Let's
increase our value a little bit.
We click on it above Standard.
What will happen with this?  The amount of our insurance will
increase by a little ₹1 to ₹150.
But here the value of our vehicle also
increases.  Also below you will see
that add zero depreciation.  If you want
zero depreciation then you can turn
it on from here.  What does it mean
?  You understand.  There is a question mark here.
Click and here you will see that it is clearly
written that this add-on enables you
to get the full cost of all damaged parts
even when your bike value depreciates.   That is,
if the value of your car decreases every year.
Ok?  The
value of the car decreases every year.  But remember, if
your vehicle ever gets damaged, then the
insurance policy will pay the entire amount here.
You do not have to pay any money separately.
Full cost means the actual cost of your vehicle.
Ok?  She will
do it for you here in the car.  Ok?  So that means there is
basically invoicing cost.  So
what will we do?  Now
many insurance policies are coming here which are
giving the benefit of zero depreciation.
Here United India
Insurance is charging ₹644.  Apart from this, IC
LBD is charging ₹2752.  So different companies have
different plans.  So right now our United
India Insurance policy has
valued our car at ₹1,24,962.  There is an
insurance policy of ₹644 which is an on damage
plan.  So we select this one.
Click on ₹644.  Now it will appear
before you here.  You have to tell
when your policy is going to expire?
So you select the date here.
After that you will see that you are
getting a discount of 25% or 4% here.
This is NCB discount.  No
Claim Bonus.  You get this if you have
not made any claim in the previous policy.  Ok?  So
after that you will continue and the
entire review will appear in front of you.  One thing to keep in
mind is that if you
want to take a better policy than this, then
I am going to give you advice on how to take it further.
Here you are being told
how much value there is.  Remember one thing
friends, this is a very important thing.
Personal Accidental Cover Immediate Buy Low.  So it is
clearly written here that it is
very important to take one year personal accidental cover.
Now remember, if you have more than one vehicle in your name
, be it a scooter or a bike or a
car, then brother, if you have already taken personal accidental cover in another policy,
then you do not need to take it again and again.
So if you have not taken it, like
in our case this is our car, then
we have only one car.  So right now we have ticked the ₹320 one
here.  That means
we will have to take it.  After that we will
come down a little bit.  You can see the rest of the things here.
Apart from this, we will have to make a total payment of ₹1137
and
if we click on inclusive of GST, then from here you will be
able to see how much is your insurance policy,
how much is the on-damage plan, personal
accidental cover and GST of ₹174 is being charged here, so let's
deduct it and
from here click on buy plan.
Now here we have not linked our bank account
in PhonePe, so now we can do it here
with our credit card or debit card.
So here you will have to enter the credit card
number and if you do not have a credit
card then you will enter your UPI PIN from your bank
and
complete the payment here.  So let us make the
payment here.  So friends, we have
completed the payment here and
after that it will appear in front of you in this way
that you have to enter your PAN card
number here in whose name the vehicle is also registered.
Ok?  In whose name there is also a scooter.
You can check it on RC.
You have to enter their PAN card number here.
What is his date of birth?  You will enter it.
You will enter the owner's name and
here you will enter the email ID i.e. Gmail ID.
After that you will submit it.
Now guys, you have to tell here
with which document you
want to do KYC because it is necessary to get KYC done here.
So now
we want to get it done through Aadhar card.  If you want, you
can also make changes here.  Ok?  So we will
upload the front and back photos here.   Also
what is the full name
on Aadhar card.  After that,
what is the last four digits of the Aadhar card and you will have to select the date of birth
here and whatever their
address is, you will fill up the complete address from
here.  Apart from that, you will enter the pin code
number and his father's name.
After that we will submit it.
After that friends, your information will
appear here in such a way that now brother, your KYC is
in process.  You will
wait for a little while and then friends, if you
check after some time, it will appear in front of you in this manner
that it will come for your download.
So you can also download the
insurance policy from here and if you want, you
can also email it from here.  So
friends, let us now talk about
which is the best company from which you should
take the scooter or bike insurance policy.
Now remember friends, the purpose of making this video was
because many people were
commenting below our video
that make a video on how to insure a scooter or bike through PhonePe, so that's why
we had to make this video, but
friends, I personally get my vehicle
insurance done from another company, so
which company is that and how
you have to do it, I have already
made a video on that, if you want to
watch the video, you will get the link in the description,
you must watch that video
and friends, if you liked the video a little, then
leave a nice comment below and if you want to see similar videos, then
subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon on all.  So that
you get updates of latest videos.